<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Greater London Linux User Group</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/</link><description>Recent content on Greater London Linux User Group</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 21:06:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gllug.org.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>pre-FOSDEM Meetup Thu 2nd Feb at the Mulberry Bush pub from 6pm</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/2017/01/16/pre-fosdem-meetup-thu-2nd-feb-at-the-mulberry-bush-pub-from-6pm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 21:06:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/2017/01/16/pre-fosdem-meetup-thu-2nd-feb-at-the-mulberry-bush-pub-from-6pm/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Happy new year all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be meeting up on the Thursday before &lt;a href="https://fosdem.org/2017/"&gt;FOSDEM&lt;/a&gt; – 2nd February from 6pm at the &lt;a href="http://www.mulberrybushpub.com/"&gt;Mulbery Bush Pub&lt;/a&gt; which is near Waterloo station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a great chance for anyone who is interested in Linux and Open Source to have a few drinks and a chat with some like-minded people in a nice informal atmosphere. Anyone and everyone is welcome, so spread the word and bring people along, especially if you’re in the area to head to FOSDEM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>FOSS Talk Live 2016, 6th August Kings Cross</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/2016/07/14/foss-talk-live-2016-6th-august-kings-cross/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 17:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/2016/07/14/foss-talk-live-2016-6th-august-kings-cross/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Much like London busses, a second London Linux event has also come along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOSS Talk Live 2016 is a free evening of Linux podcasts on Saturday 6th August at The Harrison near Kings Cross. The main event is ticketed, taking place in the basement of the pub and I expect there will be a large public social gathering upstairs in the main bar area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the tickets for the main event have been reserved but I expect that in the time between the four live shows, people will congregate upstairs and that not everyone will go down to watch every show.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Meetup Wed 27th July 2016 at The Blacksmith and Toffeemaker pub (near Angel station) from 6pm</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/2016/07/14/meetup-wed-27th-july-2016-at-the-blacksmith-and-toffeemaker-pub-near-angel-station-from-6pm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 16:24:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/2016/07/14/meetup-wed-27th-july-2016-at-the-blacksmith-and-toffeemaker-pub-near-angel-station-from-6pm/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Not to make this look like a 6 monthly meetup, but that’s what it’s going to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll be meeting on Wednesday the 27th of July 2016 from 6pm at &lt;a href="http://www.theblacksmithandthetoffeemaker.co.uk/"&gt;The Blacksmith and Toffeemaker pub&lt;/a&gt;, a 5 minute walk from Angel tube station, or just behind City University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a new venue for us, not sure what to expect. Wear a geeky shirt or t-shirt so we can identify each other, don’t forget to bring a friend.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>IRC</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/irc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 11:11:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/irc/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;You can chat to us on IRC on &lt;a href="irc://irc.freenode.org/gllug"&gt;#gllug on Freenode&lt;/a&gt; or by using &lt;a href="https://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=#gllug"&gt;Freenode’s web based IRC client&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Meetup Thu 28th Jan at the Mulberry Bush pub (near Waterloo station) 6pm</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/2016/01/05/meetup-thu-28th-jan-at-the-mulberry-bush-pub-near-waterloo-station-6pm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 18:37:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/2016/01/05/meetup-thu-28th-jan-at-the-mulberry-bush-pub-near-waterloo-station-6pm/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A new year, a new site and a new meetup!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be meeting up on the Thursday before FOSDEM – 28th January from 6pm at the &lt;a href="http://www.mulberrybushpub.com/"&gt;Mulbery Bush Pub&lt;/a&gt; which is near Waterloo station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a great chance for anyone who is into Linux and Open Source to have a few drinks and a chat with some like-minded people in a nice informal atmosphere. Anyone and everyone is welcome, so spread the word and bring people along! The pub has the usual selection of drinks and also has a pretty decent &lt;a href="http://www.mulberrybushpub.com/food"&gt;menu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the new GLLUG site</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/2015/12/21/welcome-to-the-new-gllug-site/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 10:44:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/2015/12/21/welcome-to-the-new-gllug-site/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The old site died with a database error and after several months and no improvement, I’ve decided to relaunch the site with the fantastic support of &lt;a href="http://positive-internet.com/"&gt;Positive Internet&lt;/a&gt;, who were also able to swap everything over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is still much to do, and it will take time to put everything back together but this is the first step in the right direction. I hope to see you all at a meet soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Meet Up Saturday 7th of June 2014 from 12 at South London Makerspace</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/2014/05/29/meet-up-saturday-7th-of-june-2014-from-12-at-south-london-makerspace/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 10:02:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/2014/05/29/meet-up-saturday-7th-of-june-2014-from-12-at-south-london-makerspace/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I know, I know. First meet up in a long time, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on the South London Makerspace which is now a real thing so lets meet there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The South London Makerspace is a hackerspace like community in South London with a focus on social and education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan is to meet, chat, educate. There will be informal talks, &lt;strong&gt;volunteers for talks needed&lt;/strong&gt;. I plan to give an introduction about the Makerspace.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pre-FOSDEM Drinks Thursday 31st January 2013 from 6:30pm @ Ye Olde Cock Tavern</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/2013/01/25/pre-fosdem-drinks-thursday-31st-january-2013-from-630pm-@-ye-olde-cock-tavern/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 18:19:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/2013/01/25/pre-fosdem-drinks-thursday-31st-january-2013-from-630pm-@-ye-olde-cock-tavern/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Pre-FOSDEM drinks because I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to get people involved who may be visiting in London that night because they will be heading off to FOSDEM the next day.
But even if you&amp;rsquo;re not heading to FOSDEM you should still come because not only will you be meeting a great bunch of people you&amp;rsquo;ll also be able to claim some O&amp;rsquo;Reilly merch from me including some books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll be upstairs at the top of the pub, the stairs on your right immediately as you walk in. You&amp;rsquo;ll know it&amp;rsquo;s the right place because I&amp;rsquo;ll have a Tux sitting around in the room.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Saturday 8th December 2012, 12:30pm - Greater London LUG Meetup @ Firefox Space London</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/2012/11/11/saturday-8th-december-2012-1230pm-greater-london-lug-meetup-@-firefox-space-london/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2012 10:23:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/2012/11/11/saturday-8th-december-2012-1230pm-greater-london-lug-meetup-@-firefox-space-london/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Greater London Linux User Group meet up are extremely happy to announce the next Meet up. This time it will be at the Mozilla Space in London on Saturday the 8th of December from 12.30pm. It is open and free for anyone to attend, especially to those interested in Linux, Android, Free software, open hardware and anything related to free software and it&amp;rsquo;s culture.
There will be talks from members of the community as well as the option for anyone to show off something cool too.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Thursday 20th September - Greater London LUG Drink Up</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/2012/09/01/thursday-20th-september-greater-london-lug-drink-up/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 10:34:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/2012/09/01/thursday-20th-september-greater-london-lug-drink-up/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Greater London Linux User Group are pleased to announce the next Drink Up on Thursday 20th September from 6pm at The William Blake pub on Old Street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have an are booked at the back of The William Blake pub for Thursday 20th of September from 6pm. The Drink Up is an opportunity to meet new and different people after work while having a few drinks and some food. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty close to Old Street station, does some good food and we have access to a projector and speaker system so if you would like to show something too you can. Anyone is welcome to come along, especially if they&amp;rsquo;re interested in finding out more about programming, open hardware, Linux, Ubuntu, Red Hat, Free-software and it&amp;rsquo;s culture.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Saturday 11th August 2012 @ 12pm Greater London LUG Meet up</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/2012/07/11/saturday-11th-august-2012-@-12pm-greater-london-lug-meet-up/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 17:02:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/2012/07/11/saturday-11th-august-2012-@-12pm-greater-london-lug-meet-up/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Greater London Linux User Group are excited to announce the first meeting of the group for over two years. We would like to warmly invite anyone who is keen to discover something new about Linux, Android, Free and Open Source Software, Open Hardware and Free Culture to attend and meet new people with the same interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be talks from members of the community as well as the option for anyone to show off something cool too. Followed by drinks in a local public house called The Fox from around 4pm.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>New (Temporary) Mailing List</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/2012/06/20/new-temporary-mailing-list/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 16:52:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/2012/06/20/new-temporary-mailing-list/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Due to our long-standing GLLUG maintained mailing list being out of service for over a month now we have joined forces with &lt;a href="http://lug.org.uk/"&gt;lug.org.uk&lt;/a&gt; and are now running a temporary mailing list with them. Most of the previous subscribers have been re-invited to this new list, but if you are new, welcome and please join our new list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the &lt;a href="http://mailman.lug.org.uk/mailman/listinfo/gllug"&gt;instructions for subscribing are here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Wednesday 6th June 2012 - Social Meeting</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/2012/05/17/wednesday-6th-june-2012-social-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 10:48:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/2012/05/17/wednesday-6th-june-2012-social-meeting/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After the somewhat successful relaunch of the Lincolnshire LUG and the huge turn out at the GitHub London drink up a few weeks ago it really is time to get the largest Linux user base in the UK back together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re starting out informally, just to gauge interest and to discuss plans, locations, dates etc. over a few drinks. We want as many people to come along as possible. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a GLLUG regular, or simply have an interest in finding out more about Linux or Free software.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>25th August 2011 - Celebrate the 20th anniversary of Linux</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/2011/08/11/25th-august-2011-celebrate-the-20th-anniversary-of-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 11:45:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/2011/08/11/25th-august-2011-celebrate-the-20th-anniversary-of-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On 25th August 1991 Linus Torvalds announced that he had been working on a new PC (80386) operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, 20 years later we all know and (mostly) love Linux, the fruit of his labours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To celebrate this GLLUG (and others) will meet on 25th August at Mabel&amp;rsquo;s Tavern, 9 Mabledon Place, WC1H 9AZ from 5pm onwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mabel&amp;rsquo;s Tavern is a &amp;ldquo;Shepherd Neame&amp;rdquo; pub so we can expect to drink real beer. They serve food too.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>About GLLUG</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 16:34:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/about/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;GLLUG&amp;rsquo;s purpose is to bring together London&amp;rsquo;s Linux users so they can share experiences and expertise (or revel in their inexperience and quest for expertise), to chat about the state of the (Linux) world, that sort of thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no membership fees, just pop along to a meeting, or join the mailing lists or IRC channel which you can find on the left bar.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>15th July 2010 - GLLUG Talk - The Android Kernel</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/2010/07/06/15th-july-2010-gllug-talk-the-android-kernel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2010 08:06:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/2010/07/06/15th-july-2010-gllug-talk-the-android-kernel/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The this months talk will be about the Android kernel and will be given by Sunny Aujla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He will be talking about the history, a view of android in mainstream linux, the Google changes, and the future of the Android kernel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month we have another change of venue, we are back at UCL! Ron Gaston has kindly booked room 1.02 in the Malet Place Engineering Building which if I remember correctly you have to enter through the Roberts building.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>17th June - GLLUG Talk - Typesetting with Free Software Tools</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/2010/06/02/17th-june-gllug-talk-typesetting-with-free-software-tools/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2010 09:30:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/2010/06/02/17th-june-gllug-talk-typesetting-with-free-software-tools/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday, June 17th, 2010
Time: 7:30pm – 9:30pm
Location: Univ of Westminster Campus
Street: New Cavendish Street
City/Town: London&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.openstreetmap.org/index.html?mlat=51.520918&amp;amp;mlon=-0.140103&amp;amp;zoom=14"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next talk is titled &amp;ldquo;Typesetting with Free Software Tools&amp;rdquo; and will be given by Tethys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After being introduced to the wonders of Unix at university, Tethys was hooked. With the release of Linux a few years later, he was able to use Unix at home as well, and has never looked back. He has interests in digital typography, large system design, and playing with LARTC. His career has alternated between coding and sysadmin for various companies in various industries. One of those was in the pre-press department of a large newspaper group, where an interest in typesetting became a profession for a while. He is currently at the coding end of the spectrum, writing software for a small company using statistical analysis to predict future trends.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>13th May - Joint GLLUG / UKUUG talk</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/2010/05/10/13th-may-joint-gllug-/-ukuug-talk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 12:12:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/2010/05/10/13th-may-joint-gllug-/-ukuug-talk/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday, May 13, 2010
Time: 7:00pm
Venue: Lecture theatre 1.03 in the Malet Place Engineering Building, University College London
&lt;a href="http://www.ucl.ac.uk/maps/ucl-maps/map2_hi_res"&gt;Map&lt;/a&gt;
City/Town: London&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux is Supercomputing – how Linux works on your mobile phone and on the biggest supercomputers on the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eng Lim Goh of SGI will be discussing how Linux is used on supercomputers, and will demonstrate some of the capabilities of the new SGI Ultraviolet architecture, which is the most scalable Linux architecture in the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>15th April - Greater London LUG meeting</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/2010/03/29/15th-april-greater-london-lug-meeting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2010 08:39:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/2010/03/29/15th-april-greater-london-lug-meeting/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday, April 15, 2010
Time: 7:30pm – 9:30pm
Location: Univ of Westminster Campus
Street: New Cavendish Street
City/Town: London&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.openstreetmap.org/index.html?mlat=51.520918&amp;amp;mlon=-0.140103&amp;amp;zoom=14"&gt;Map&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next talk is titled &amp;ldquo;Wire Shark and the basics of network traffic monitoring.&amp;rdquo; and will be given by Nahual Marisi and John Sharp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a slight change of venue, we will still be meeting at the University of Westminster (Cavendish Campus), but in Room C1.04. If people could arrive for 1900, ready for the talk to begin at 1930. I will try and get some signs made up to direct people to room C1.04 Hopefully there will be a trip to a local pub for social and technical chit-chat.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>18th March - Greater London LUG Meeting</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/2010/03/02/18th-march-greater-london-lug-meeting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 12:42:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/2010/03/02/18th-march-greater-london-lug-meeting/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday, March 18, 2010
Time: 7:30pm – 9:30pm
Location: Univ of Westminster Campus
Street: New Cavendish Street
City/Town: London&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.openstreetmap.org/index.html?mlat=51.520918&amp;amp;mlon=-0.140103&amp;amp;zoom=14"&gt;Map&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be a talk for the GLLUG by Richard Jones on libguestfs[1] on Thursday 18th March at 1930. It will be held at the Cavendish campus of the University of Westminster, in the Large Lecture Theatre. I will try and get a more accurate description of the lecture theatre&amp;rsquo;s location and post it to the mailing list and website. If people could arrive at 1900 to make sure we are ready to begin at 1930. After the talk I suggest we go to a decent local pub for a social.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>19th Nov 2009 : Social Meeting</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/2009/11/04/19th-nov-2009-social-meeting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2009 23:53:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/2009/11/04/19th-nov-2009-social-meeting/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Venue : &lt;a href="http://www.individualpubs.co.uk/pembury/"&gt;Pembury Tavern&lt;/a&gt;
Date and Time : 19th November 1930 til &amp;ldquo;late&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Person to find there : Ciarán Mooney, who might or might not &lt;a href="http://pyuk2008.pyconuk.org/images/ciaranmooney.png"&gt;look like this guy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have a &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/event.php?eid=167818403148&amp;amp;ref=nf"&gt;Facebook event page&lt;/a&gt; for this.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>500 – Server Error</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/error_pages/500.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/error_pages/500.html</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Something went wrong on the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please get in touch with one of the contact details to let us know this happened.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Page Not Found</title><link>https://gllug.org.uk/error_pages/404.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gllug.org.uk/error_pages/404.html</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Sorry, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t find that page.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>